New American Poetry Circuit Records
© 2002 University of Connecticut
New American Poetry Circuit Records.
1969-1974.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
New American Poetry Circuit.
1 linear foot.
San Francisco based cooperative that existed from 1969 to 1971, organized to arrange and promote poetry readings by its members; Jeanetta L. Jones, Director. Members included: D. Alexander, David Antin, Harvey Bialy, Paul Blackburn, Victor Coleman, Ed Dorn, Theodore Enslin, Clayton Eshleman, Larry Goodell, Jack Hirschman, Anselm Hollo, Kenneth Irby, Robert Kelly, Phillip Lamantia, Jackson MacLow, Michael McClure, Daphne Marlatt, David Meltzer, Jerome Rothenburg, Armand Schwerner, Charles Stein, Diane Wakoski. Among these poets were some of the most promising talents in literary circles at the time of the founding of the circuit, and Jeanetta had hoped to exploit their fame to the best advantage of all the poets in the co-op through some joint readings in some of the universities and colleges. Unfortunately, most of the lesser known poets could not garner the expected recognition and readings through the efforts of the circuit, and because of that Jeanetta felt compelled to give up at the end of the first season in 1971.
MSS19980206
History:
A cooperative organized to arrange and promote poetry readings for its registered poets in universities and colleges; founded and directed by Jeanetta L. Jones from an office in Berkeley, California. The idea of the cooperative was mooted by Jeanetta Jones through her correspondence with Clayton Eshleman. Both of them were poets, though Eshleman already had a following and had produced some anthology collections. Ms. Jones sent out brochures that contained biographical data of the poets to all prospective clients throughout the country. Members included: D. Alexander, David Antin, Harvey Bialy, Paul Blackburn, Victor Coleman, Ed Dorn, Theodore Enslin, Clayton Eshleman, Larry Goodell, Jack Hirschman, Anselm Hollo, Kenneth Irby, Robert Kelly, Phillip Lamantia, Jack MacLow, Michael McClure, Daphne Marlatt, David Meltzer, Jerome Rothenberg, Armand Schwerner, Charles Stei, and Diane Wakoski.
Scope and Content:
The collection includes correspondence and manuscripts of members (except for Charles Stein); correspondence and manuscripts of prospective members; business records and promotional materials.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to literature. See especially, the papers of Ed Dorn and Robert Kelly. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Bibliography
The New American Poetry Circuit: First Season, 1970 - 71 ( San Francisco, 1970).
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Jones, Jenetta L.; Antin, David.; Blackburn, Paul.; Coleman, Victor, 1944-; Dorn, Edward.; Enslin, Theodore.; Eshleman, Clayton.; Goodell, Larry, 1935-; Hirschman, Jack, 1933-; Hollo, Anselm.; Irby, Kenneth, 1936-; Kelly, Robert, 1935-; Lamantia, Philip, 1927-; McClure, Michael.; Marlatt, Daphne.; Meltzer, David.; Rothenberg, Jerome, 1931-; Schwerner, Armand.; Wakoski, Diane.
Subjects:
American poetry--20th century.; American poetry--California.; American poetry--Societies, etc.; Oral interpretation of poetry--Societies, etc.; Cooperative societies.; San Francisco (Calif.)--Cultural affairs--Literature.; California--Societies, etc.--Cultural.; San Francisco (Calif.)--Societies, etc.-Cultural.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Custodial History
Jeanetta Jones donated the collection to Archives & Special Collections.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Correspondence,1969-1974
  - Subseries A: Member Correspondence,1969-1973
    - Alexander, D., 1971 (Box 1:1)
    - Antin, David, 1969-1971 (Box 1:2)
    - Bialy, Timothy, 1969-1973 (Box 1:3)
    - Blackburn, Paul, 1969-1970 (Box 1:4)
    - Coleman, Victor, 1969-1971 (Box 1:5)
    - Dorn, Ed, 1969-1971 (Box 1:6)
    - Enslin, Theodore, 1969-1971 (Box 1:7)
    - Eshleman, Clayton, 1969-1973 (Box 1:8)
    - Goodell, Larry, 1969-1971 (Box 1:9)
    - Hirschman, Jack, 1969-1973 (Box 1:10)
    - Hollo, Anselm, 1969-1971 (Box 1:11)
    - Irby, Ken, 1969-1970 (Box 1:12)
    - Kelly, Robert, 1969-1970 (Box 1:13)
    - Lamantia, Philip, 1969-1970 (Box 1:14)
    - MacLow, Jackson, 1969 (Box 1:15)
    - McClure, Michael, 1969-1971 (Box 1:16)
    - Marlatt, Daphne, 1969-1971 (Box 1:17)
    - Meltzer, David, 1969-1970 (Box 1:18)
    - Meltzer, David, 1969-1971 (Box 1:19)
    - Schwerner, Armand, 1969-1971 (Box 1:20)
    - Wakoski, Diane, 1969-1972 (Box 1:21)
  - Subseries B: Alphabetical non-member Correspondence, 1969-1974
    - A - B, 1969-1971 (Box 1:22)
    - C - D, 1969-1971 (Box 1:23)
    - E - F, 1969-1972 (Box 1:24)
    - G - H, 1969-1971 (Box 1:25)
    - I - J, 1972 (Box 2:26)
    - K - L, 1969-1970 (Box 2:27)
    - M - N, 1969-1971 (Box 2:28)
    - O - P, 1969-1972 (Box 2:29)
    - Q -R, 1970-1972 (Box 2:30)
    - S - T, 1969-1974 (Box 2:31)
    - U - V - W, 1969-1971 (Box 2:32)
    - X - Y - Z, 1969-1970 (Box 2:33)
    - Outgoing Correspondence, 1969-1971 (Box 2:34)
- Series II: Business Records, undated, 1969-1973
  - Brochures, undated (Box 2:35)
  - Bills and Records, 1969-1973 (Box 2:36)